#### **CURRICULUM VITAE**

#### **MESHACK WAMBUA PIUS**

P.O Box 45-90200,

**KITUI** 

Tel: +254 703 103 827

Email: wambuameshack2@gmail.com

#### **Personal Details**

**Gender:** Male **Year of birth:** 1994

**Language:** English, Swahili & Kamba (Proficiency in written and spoken)

**ID Number:** 30358390

#### **Personal Profile Statement**

I am a committed, hardworking and reliable statistician with a strong statistical background and a positive attitude to challenges and opportunities. I have previously worked in a busy, a fast-paced and challenging environments with a track record of effective data management, resulting in reduced costs and increased operational efficiency. I take ownership of my tasks, and I'm willing to go extra mile to deliver and exceed expectations where possible. My current role involves collecting, collating and compiling data, and preparation of technical reports. However, prioritizing any work activities is a key strength that I have developed.

## **Achievements**

- Attained a first class degree in statistics
- Three recommendation letters from former employers and current employer

#### **Education**

- **2013-2017 : Bachelor of Science Statistics**, Meru University of Science & Technology *Grade Achieved:* First class Honours
- 2008 -2012: Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education, Katheka Boys' Sec School *Grade Achieved*: B<sup>+</sup> (Plus); AGP =72 Points
- 2000-2007: Kenya Certificate of Primary Education, Kiukuni Primary School *Marks Scored*: 300 Marks

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

March 2021- Present: Economist/Statistician Intern

**Kenya National Bureau of Statistics (KNBS)** 

Duties & Responsibilities

- Collecting, collating and compiling data
- Following up data requests from data producers and responding to data user's requests

- Support the coordination and supervision of data collection activities
- Extract data and prepare analytical files
- Assisting in the development and review of data collection tools
- Perform exploratory and advanced statistical analysis of data
- Participating in county meetings and trainings

# July 2019 –Dec 2020: Freelancer Data Analyst Online Academic writing & Research

## **Duties & Responsibilities**

As a freelancer Data Analyst, I have handled large datasets in my online academic writing platform, both for my colleagues and professors. In my profession as a data analyst, I have gained skills in:

- Data management
- Data analysis using R, SPSS, STATA and advanced Microsoft Excel
- Project Management
- Report writing
- Research proposal & project writing

# April 2019 – June 2019: Registration Assistant (RA) National Integrated Identity Management System (NIIMS)

## Duties & Responsibilities

- National Biometric Registration of all citizens and foreign Nationals residing in Kenya at sub-location level.
- Filing daily reports on registration records.
- Biometric Kits management
- Data entry and data validation
- Data collection
- Information capture by use of Biometric Kits and Data capture forms.

# Aug –Oct 2017: Researcher / Data Analyst Intern Kenyatta National Hospital

#### Duties & Responsibilities

- Data collection and data validation.
- Statistical data analysis using Advanced Excel, SPPS, and STATA.
- Developing monthly quarterly reports.
- Report writing based on the findings of the research study.
- Data entry using the EPI DATA software
- Designing research tool (Questionnaires)
- Data cleaning/data error correction.

## **SKILLS**

- Computer Literacy: I am computer literate with in-depth knowledge of Microsoft word ,Excel, and Power point
- **Statistical programming:** Competent in analysing quantitative and qualitative data using statistical software such as SPSS, EXCEL & R.

## OTHER WORKING EXPERIENCE

• **2019 October**: Deputy Presiding Officer at IEBC (Mutonguni ward by-election)

• Jan -Sept 2018: Maths tutor, Advent college-Nairobi

• **2017 August:** E.V.I.D Clerk no.1, I.E.B.C Kitui County.

• May - Aug 2013: Maths/Business Teacher at Kitamwiki Secondary School.

## **REFEREES**

## Mr. Reuben K. Mwinzi

County Statistics Officer, Kenya National Bureau of Statistics (KNBS) P.O Box 45-90200

Kitui.

Email: rmwinzi@knbs.or.ke

Tel: +254 720362532

## Mr. Vincent Chagara

Statistician, Kenyatta National Hospital, P.O Box 20723-00202

Nairobi.

Email: vincentchagara@gmail.com

Tel: +254 715447008

## Mr Henry Karuti

Economist, Kenyatta National Hospital, P.O Box 20723-00202 Nairobi.

Email: <u>h2karuti@gmail.com</u> TEL: +254 710840445